  <tutorial>
    <title>Lesson 3 - Basic anatomy of a protocol in Quint</title>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <description>
In this tutorial, we explain the standard structure of a Quint protocol.
Although Quint does not impose a very rigid structure on protocol designers,
we have found that following common practices helps protocol authors and
their readers to cooperate more effectively.

As a running example, we are using the subcurrency smart contract that
is introduced in the Solidity documentation, see
[Subcurrency](https://docs.soliditylang.org/en/v0.8.17/introduction-to-smart-contracts.html#subcurrency-example).
You do not have to know Solidity to understand this tutorial.
On the contrary, you may acquire some basic understanding of Solidity contracts
by reading the Quint protocol specification.

The subcurrency smart contract defines a basic protocol that has the following features:

 - A single user (the protocol creator) is assigned the "minter" role.

 - The minter may generate new coins on the balances of the users, including themselves.

 - The users may send coins to other users, provided that they have enough coins
   on their balance.

In this tutorial, you will see how to:

 - Specify basic type aliases.

 - Define handy functions that can be used independently of the protocol.

 - Define the structure of the protocol states.

 - Define helper functions that read the current state, but do not modify it.

 - Define actions that read and modify the current state of the protocol.

 - Define basic protocol invariants.

 - Write basic protocol tests.

 - Write protocol tests that use input non-determinism.

 - Run a basic randomized test to discover an invariant violation.

        <!-- The following reference is useless in CodeTour, as it already positioned on the file -->
        <block target="markdown">
If you would like to see the complete code before diving into
the details, check [coin.qnt](https://github.com/informalsystems/quint/tree/main/examples/tutorials/coin.qnt).
        </block>
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>16</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Declare a single module</title>
        <description>
Quint specifications are organized in modules, and may consist of one or many
top-level module declarations.
Nested module declarations are currently not supported.

In this tutorial, we declare a single module. In general, we recommend to start
with a single module and introduce multiple modules only if you are going to
reuse various parts of your protocol.
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>17</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Declare types</title>
        <description>
Similar to programming languages, it is common in Quint to declare type
aliases for the types that appear in the protocol description often.
A type alias is simply a declaration of the form:

```scala
type [name] = [tp];
```

In the above definition, `[name]` is a unique identifier that will be associated
with the type, and `[tp]` is the type to be associated with the name, e.g.,
`int` or `Set[int]`. To see a complete description of all available types, visit the Section
[Type System 1.2](https://github.com/informalsystems/quint/blob/main/docs/content/docs/lang.md#type-system-12)
of the language manual.

Although it is convenient to declare type aliases, it is not mandatory.
Protocol authors should decide together with their audience, whether they prefer
minimal type definitions, or they like abundance of types. Quint replaces type aliases
with the types on the right-hand sides of `type`. For example, it does not distinguish between
different kinds of "integers", when they are referred to via different type aliases.
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>28</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Declare pure functions</title>
        <description>

It often happens that a protocol requires auxiliary definitions that do not
depend on the protocol state, but only on the values of their parameters.
Such computations are often called "pure". In the above code, we define two
pure definitions:
 
 - The pure value `MAX_UINT`.

 - The pure definition `isUInt` that computes if a given integer `i` is within
   the range from 0 to MAX_UINT (inclusive).

The main property of pure values is that they always return the same value.
Pure definitions always return the same value, if they are supplied with the
same arguments.

To see that no state is needed, evaluate these definitions in REPL
(read-evaluate-print-loop):

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin "MAX_UINT"</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin "MAX_UINT"</run>

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin "isUInt(22)"</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin "isUInt(22)"</run>

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin "isUInt(-1)"</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin "isUInt(-1)"</run>

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin "isUInt(MAX_UINT + 1)"</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin "isUInt(MAX_UINT + 1)"</run>

            <block>
The functional layer is actually quite powerful; a lot of protocol behavior can
be defined here without referring to protocol state.

As you can see, we have omitted the type of `MAX_UINT` but specified the type of
`isUInt`. Most of the time, the type checker can infer the types of values and
operator definitions, and giving additional type annotations is up to you. In
rare cases, the type checker may get confused, and then explicit type
annotations will help you in figuring out the issue.
            </block>
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>37</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Declare the protocol parameters</title>
        <description>

In this step, we are starting to describe the protocol structure and behavior
in terms of a state machine.        

It often happens that protocols are parameterized in the sense that the protocol
may be instantiated for different parameter values, and different instances
still make sense. The typical parameters are:

 - the set of all possible addresses,

 - the address that performs a special role,

 - minimal and maximal values,

 - timeout values.

For this purpose, Quint offers `const` declarations. You can see one of them
in the commented out section of the code above. You may be wondering, what is
the difference between `const` and `pure val`. They mean to express the same
concept: A value that stays the same for all computations. However, they differ
in the time when they are bound to a value:

 - The `pure val` values are immediately defined via an expression in the
   right-hand side.

 - The `const` values are first declared and later they are substituted
   with actual values via an `instance` declaration.

At the moment, we simply declare the value for a small set of addresses `ADDR`,
in order to be able to iterate on the protocol specification quickly.
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>46</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Declare the protocol state</title>
        <description>

As a next step, we declare state variables, which together represent
a state of the protocol. In the above code, we introduce two such variables:

 - The variable `minter` to store the minter's address.
   The type of this variable is `Addr`.

 - The variable `balances` to store the balances of all users.
   The type of this variable is `Addr -> UInt`, which means a map from
   values of type `Addr` to values of type `UInt`.

Variable definitions always require type. Otherwise, it may be too hard
for the type checker to infer the types of the state variables.

If you compare the above variable definitions to the relevant variable
declarations in the Solidity contract, you should see that our variable
declarations are conceptually similar, modulo the slightly different syntax
of Solidity:


```Solidity
    // in Solidity:
    address public minter;
    mapping (address => uint) public balances;
```    
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>51</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Declare operators over states</title>
        <description>

It is often convenient to define a few helper operators.

We start with the definition of `state` that represents the entire
state as a record. This is what we do in the above code with the definition of
`state`. Notice that the definition of `state` is prefixed with `val`, not `pure val`.
Since `state` accesses state variables is it impure.

You can try to evaluate the definition of `state` in REPL right away:

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin "state"</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin "state"</run>

            <block>
If you tried that, you saw several error messages. The reason is that the state
variables are not initialized by default. We would have to introduce an
initialization action, which is usually called `init`. You will see how to
do that a few steps later.
            </block>
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>53</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Declare `require` and `totalSupply`</title>
        <description>

In the above code, we introduce a helper definition `require` that
evaluates its Boolean parameter. As you might have noticed, this
definition is not doing anything useful. We introduce it to make the code
a bit more accessible for first-time readers who are familiar with
Solidity.

The definition of `totalSupply` may look a bit complex,
if you have never seen similar code before. Let's break it down into smaller
pieces:

 - The definition of `totalSupply` defines a value, but not a `pure` one.
   Hence, even though `totalSupply` does not take any parameters,
   it implicitly depends on the state. As a result, `totalSupply`
   may evaluate to different values in different states, that is,
   in those states where the values of `balances` differ.

 - `ADDR.fold(0, f)` iterates over the set of addresses in *some order*
   and for every address `a`, it applies `f(s, a)` for the accumulator value `s`,
   which is initialized with 0. In our example, the operator `f` is defined as
   an anonymous lambda operator: `(sum, a) => sum + balances.get(a)`. For our
   definition of `ADDR`, the computed value would be equal to:

   ```scala
    ((((0 + balances.get("null")) + balances.get("alice")) + balances.get("bob"))
      + balances.get("charlie")) + balances.get("eve")
   ```

   *Note that the order of the addresses in the brackets may be different from
   the one above. Hence, you should not rely on a particular order when
   using `fold` over sets. We are fine when using commutative operators such as `+` and `*`.*

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>59</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Declare an initializer `init`</title>
        <description>

As you may have seen in the previous steps, the state variables `minter` and `balances`
are not initialized by default. In order to compute an initial state (there may be
several!), we define a special action that we call an *initializer*. In our
code, such an action is called `init`.

This definition is essential for describing the protocol. When you read somebody else's
protocol, it is one of the key parts to look at.

If we go back to the Solidity code, it looks as follows:

```Solidity
    // in Solidity
    constructor() {
        minter = msg.sender;
    }
```

In the Solidity code, the constructor is using an implicit parameter `msg.sender`,
which is propagated from a user request by the Ethereum Virtual Machine. Quint
does not have any built-in mechanism for reading user input. Instead, Quint
offers a very powerful mechanism of non-deterministic choice. This is
exactly what we do with the following line of code:

```scala
nondet sender = oneOf(ADDR)
```

This expression non-deterministically chooses one value from the set `ADDR`
(assuming that the set is not empty) and binds this value to the name `sender`.
The qualifier `nondet` indicates that the value of `sender` is special: the
name `sender` is bound to a fixed value, but `sender` *may evaluate to two
different values* when `init` is called twice or is called in different runs.
This behavior may look
complicated, but this is exactly what we expect from user input, too:
The user may submit different inputs, even if the protocol resides in
two identical states.

For more details, check
[oneOf](https://github.com/informalsystems/quint/blob/main/docs/content/docs/builtin.md#oneof)
in the reference manual.

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>65</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Assign initial values to the state variables</title>
        <description>

The rest of `init` is simple:
The value of `minter` is set to the value of `sender`, and the value
of `balances` is set to the map that maps all addresses from `ADDR`
to value 0. Notice that the variables `minter` and `balances` are not assigned
their new values immediately; they are assigned once `init` is
evaluated completely (and only if `init` evaluated to `true`).

Now we can call `init` and evaluate an initialized state in REPL:

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin "init" "state"</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin "init" "state"</run>

            <block>
**Exercise:** Call `init` multiple times in REPL and evaluate `state` after
each call. Did you get the same initial states every time or were some states
different?

Remember that we called `init` an initializer? This is because `init`
only assigns new values to state variables, but does not read their previous values.

**Exercise:** Modify the assignment to `balances` in such a way that `minter`
gets 1000 coins, while the other addresses get 0 coins, as before.
Hint: use `if (cond) value1 else value2`.
            </block>

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>70</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Defining the action `send`</title>
        <description>

Similar to Solidity, we define the action `mint`. In contrast to `init`,
we have decided to avoid non-deterministic choice in `mint`.
Instead we are passing the user inputs as action parameters. You will see
later that this makes debugging and testing easier.

If you understood how `init` works, the behavior of `mint` should be also
easy to figure out. If you wonder what `get` and `set` are doing, here is
the explanation:

 - `balances.get(receiver)` produces the value assigned to the key `receiver`
   in the map `balances`. If the key `receiver` has no value assigned in
   the map `balances`, REPL would show a runtime error.
   For more details, check
   [get](https://github.com/informalsystems/quint/blob/main/docs/content/docs/builtin.md#get)
   in the reference manual.

 - `balances.set(receiver, newBal)` produces a new map, that assigns
   the value of `newBal` to the key `receiver`, and keeps the other key-value
   pairs as in `balances`.
   For more details, check
   [set](https://github.com/informalsystems/quint/blob/main/docs/content/docs/builtin.md#set)
   in the reference manual.

Now it's time to mint some coins in REPL! Try the following:

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin 'init' 'mint(minter, "bob", 2023)' 'state'</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin 'init' 'mint(minter, "bob", 2023)' 'state'</run>

            <block>
As you can see, we can mint coins for Bob.

**Exercise:** Mint more coins for Bob, actually, mint `MAX_UINT` coins.
Do you understand what happened in this case?
            </block>

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>87</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Defining the action `send`</title>
        <description>

If you understood the mechanics of the action `mint`, you should easily
figure out the behavior of `send`.

Play with `mint` and `send` in REPL! The simplest scenario would be:

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin 'init' 'mint(minter, "bob", 2023)' 'send("bob", "eve", 1024)' 'state'</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin 'init' 'mint(minter, "bob", 2023)' 'send("bob", "eve", 1024)' 'state'</run>

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>113</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Defining a protocol step</title>
        <description>

Finally, we can put together `mint` and `send` to describe every possible
transition of the protocol! To this end, we non-deterministically choose
the sender, the receiver, and the amount (from the set of integers from 0
to `MAX_UINT`, inclusive). The expression `any { ... }` executes one of its
arguments; if both could be executed, one of them is executed
non-deterministically.

**Exercise:** Run REPL, execute `init` once and execute `step` multiple times.
Do you understand why some of the occurrences of `step` evaluate to `false`
and some evaluate to `true`? It may help you, if you print `state` after `init`
and `step`.

We have defined the state variables, the initializer, and a step of the protocol.
This is the minimal set of tasks for defining a working protocol.
What we have achieved here is great! You can play with the protocol, feed it
with different parameters in REPL, and experiment with your protocol.

Although you should definitely play with the protocol at this point, we urge you
not to stop here! In the next steps, we show you the real magic of Quint.
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>125</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Expected properties</title>
        <description>

Having defined the protocol behavior with `init` and `step`, it is time to think
about what we expect from the protocol. This is a good place for specifying
protocol invariants and temporal properties.

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>127</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Defining the most basic invariant</title>
        <description>

One of the most basic properties that we expect from the protocol is defined
by the property `balancesRangeInv`. This property goes over all addresses
in `ADDR` and tests, whether the value stored in `balances` for every address
is in the range from `0` to `MAX_UINT` (inclusive).

We can immediately check this invariant for a few states:

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin 'init' 'balancesRangeInv' 'mint(minter, "bob", 2023)' 'balancesRangeInv' 'send("bob", "eve", 1024)' 'balancesRangeInv'</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin 'init' 'balancesRangeInv' 'mint(minter, "bob", 2023)' 'balancesRangeInv' 'send("bob", "eve", 1024)' 'balancesRangeInv'</run>

            <block>
Properties like `balancesRangeInv` are called *invariants*, because we expect
them to hold in every state that could be produced by `init` and a number of
`step` actions. Intuitively, whatever happens, the property should hold true.

It is important to distinguish between the properties that we would like to be
invariants and the properties that we have proven to be invariants.
To be precise, the former properties are called *invariant candidates*,
whereas the latter are actually called *invariants*.
            </block>

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>133</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Defining the total supply invariant</title>
        <description>

Another basic invariant that we intuitively expect to hold is defined in
`totalSupplyDoesNotOverflowInv`. It is so simple that it should hold true, right?
If we have your attention now, read further!

**Exercise:** Extend the protocol with a state variable called `totalMinted`,
initialize it with 0 and increase it in `mint` with the `amount` passed to `mint`.

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>140</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Temporal properties</title>
        <description>

After we have defined state invariants, we should normally think about
temporal properties in general such as safety and liveness. However, 
temporal properties are an advanced topic, and smart
contracts are typically focused on safety. Thus, it is safe to skip this topic
for now. It is just important to know that temporal properties are labelled
with the qualifier `temporal`.

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>148</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Tests</title>
        <description>

So far, we have been running sequences of actions in REPL, to get
basic understanding of the protocol mechanics. While REPL is capable of
replaying actions one-by-one, it would be more convenient to run something
similar to unit tests or integration tests, which are ubiquitous in
programming languages.

We normally add tests in the very bottom of the protocol module, or in
a separate module.

Quint introduces *runs* to express "happy paths" and tests. The above code
shows a simple test `sendWithoutMintTest`.
In this test, the action `init` runs first. If it evaluates to `true`,
then the action `send(...)` is run. Since this action is composed with
`fail()`, the action `send(...)` is expected to evaluate to `false`.

Go ahead and see if this test goes through:

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin 'sendWithoutMintTest'</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin 'sendWithoutMintTest'</run>

            <block>
**Exercise:** Actually, if you look carefully at the code of `send`,
you can find one value for `amount` that makes `send` work even without
prior minting. What is this value?
            </block>
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>156</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>A single data point test</title>
        <description>

We can write longer tests that are similar to unit/integration tests
in normal programming languages. For instance, the above test `mintSendTest`
makes sure that the exact sequence of `mint` and `send` transactions goes
through and the resulting balances have the expected values.

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin 'mintSendTest'</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin 'mintSendTest'</run>

            <block>
**Exercise:** Change some numbers in the test, run it again in REPL and observe
what happens.

Although it is better to have a test like `mintSendTest` than no test at all,
`mintSendTest` is testing only one data point. We can do better in Quint,
see the next step.
            </block>

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>168</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Testing with non-deterministic inputs</title>
        <description>

Instead of testing a sequence of transactions for a carefully crafted
single input, we could fix a sequence of transactions and let the computer
find the inputs that fail the test. This is exactly what we are doing in
the above test `mintTwiceThenSendError`. The test non-deterministically
chooses the amounts of coins to mint and send and then executes the actions
`mint`, `mint`, and `send`. As the values are chosen non-deterministically,
we know that some of the inputs should fail `send`. Our hypothesis is that
`send` should never fail when Eve has enough coins on her account.
If she does not, we simply ignore this choice of inputs in the else-branch.

Let's run this test:

            <run target="markdown">quint -r coin.qnt::coin 'mintTwiceThenSendError'</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint -r ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt::coin 'mintTwiceThenSendError'</run>
            
            <block>

If you lucky, it fails right away. If it does not fail, run it multiple times,
until it fails. To see why it failed, evaluate `state` after executing
the test. Do you understand why our hypothesis was wrong?

**Exercise:** Fix the condition in `mintTwiceThenSendError`,
so that the test never fails.

If you carefully look at `mintTwiceThenSendError`, you will see that it is still
a single data point test, though the data point (the inputs) are chosen
non-deterministically every time we run the test. In fact, REPL implements
non-determinism via random choice.

If you do not want to sit the whole day and run the test, you could integrate
it into continuous integration, so it runs from time to time for different
inputs. Quint comes with the command `test` that is designed for exactly this
purpose. Try the command below. Most likely, it would find a violation
after just a few tests.
          </block>

          <run target="markdown">quint test --match mintTwiceThenSendError coin.qnt</run>
          <run target="codetour">quint test --match mintTwiceThenSendError ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</run>

          <block>
Also, we had to fix the sequence of actions in our test. We can do
better with Quint.

            </block>
        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>192</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Testing with non-deterministic inputs and control</title>
        <description>

It is often hard to find a good sequence of actions that breaks an invariant.
Similar to how we let the computer to find the right inputs, we can use the
computing power to look for bad sequences of actions.

Quint REPL actually supports random search for sequences of actions that violate
an invariant. Its UX is a bit ad hoc at the moment. We will improve it in the
future. You can try it right away:

            <run target="markdown">quint run --invariant totalSupplyDoesNotOverflowInv coin.qnt</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint run --invariant totalSupplyDoesNotOverflowInv ./lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</run>

            <block>

The above command in REPL randomly produces sequences of steps,
starting with `init` and continuing with `step`, up to 20 steps. It checks the
invariant `totalSupplyDoesNotOverflowInv` after every step. If the invariant is
violated, the random search stops and returns `false`. If no invariant violaion
is found, the search returns `true` after enumerating the specified number of runs,
which is 10000 in our example. The search parameters such as the number of
runs and steps can be tuned. Check the options of `run`:

            </block>

            <run target="markdown">quint run --help</run>
            <run target="codetour">quint run --help</run>

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>197</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <title>Does random testing always find bugs?</title>
        <description>

To be honest, our example is relatively simple, and we were quite lucky
that the invariant `totalSupplyDoesNotOverflowInv` was often violated by
a completely random search. For more complex protocols, random search
often gets stuck while looking for non-interesting inputs or sequences
of actions. Hence, if you have a hunch about where an error could potentially
be, you could restrict the scope of the search by:

 - Restricting the scope of non-determinstic choices, e.g.,
   by making every set in `oneOf(S)` smaller.

 - Restricting the choice of actions, e.g., by removing non-essential
   actions from `step`.

Although the above tricks may help you in detecting some bugs, it is well
known that there is always a probability of missing a bug with random search.

If you are looking for better guarantees of correctness, Quint will be soon
integrated with the
[Apalache model checker](https://github.com/apalache-mc/apalache).
The model checker looks for counterexamples more exhaustively, by solving
equations. In some cases, it may even give you a guarantee that there is no bug,
if it has not found any.

        </description>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>198</line>
      </step>
      <step>
        <file>lesson3-anatomy/coin.qnt</file>
        <line>199</line>
        <title>Suming it up</title>
        <description>

This was a long tutorial. We have specified the whole protocol,
experimented with it, wrote several tests and even found some surprising
behavior of this protocol. We hope that by going through this tutorial
you have got an idea of how you could specify your own protocol in Quint
and make Quint useful for solving your problems with protocols!

We have used a Solidity contract as the running example. Actually,
there is not much special about Solidity in this coin protocol.
A similar protocol could be implemented in
[Cosmos SDK](https://tutorials.cosmos.network/)
or [Cosmwasm](https://cosmwasm.com/).

We are experimenting with different kinds of tutorials.
It would be great to learn whether you liked this tutorial format, or not.
Please vote in the
[discussion](https://github.com/informalsystems/quint/discussions/595).
        </description>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </tutorial>
